JACKSON HOYT

SUMMARY

Proficient in advanced data analytics with several years delivering data-centric SaaS solutions within and for Walmart, solving syndicated consumer behavior, supply chain, and retail challenges.

Experienced in managing relationships at all levels of leadership and translating business user stories into tech milestones.

EDUCATION

BS Supply Chain Management Minor Information Systems

University of Arkansas

益 2014

ACHIEVEMENTS



Optimized Safety Stock ETL

Led a project to modernize ETL infrastructure for Safety Stock, impacting inventory decisions on 400M+ skus across 4500+ stores.



Data Quality Improvements

Automated QA checks with logging for Safety Stock, spotting errors caused by input data and improved key relationships.



Streamlined Category Line Reviews

Saved 1400+ hours annually by utilizing stakeholder input to create a line review template that could be automated.



Integrating With Client **Platforms**

Embedded Nielsen Panel data in Walmart's internal flagship reporting platform using Looker.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python SQL/T-SQL Excel Airflow Git GCP BigQuery Azure Snowflake Tableau MicroStrategy Looker

G-Suite Microsoft Office

Agile Scrum

EXPERIENCE

Senior Manager Advanced Analytics

Walmart

=== 11/2021 - 05/2024

Bentonville, AR

Designed and orchestrated Safety Stock SaaS solutions for Walmart US Stores

- Engineered ETL pipeline for 400M+ skus on Granular Safety Stock (BigQuery, Airflow)
- Utilized Google Cloud data warehouse, data lake, and APIs (BigQuery, GCS, Python)
- Performed routine data mining to identify emerging trends (SQL, Tableau, PowerBI)
- A/B testing used to validate business strategy changes (SQL)
- Managed product strategy, timelines, key relationships within Merchandise Operations
- Grew stakeholders by integrating 24 holiday events and 200K e-comm skus
- Secured data science resource to build predictive, machine learning inventory tool

Associate Director Data Applications

NielsenIQ

Led team of 10 in delivering flagship reporting platform One Version of Truth

- Led product roadmap for OVT using agile methodologies, securing Walmart relationship and enabling \$100M in other subscription revenues (Jira, Agile, Scrum)
- Facilitated ongoing partnership and sales opportunities by turning client needs into new capabilities, including 5 new data models
- Managed execution of GTM business intelligence products
- Regularly presented to and aligned business development targets with senior leaders
- Planned data migration to **Snowflake** and efforts to reduce tech debt
- Refactored 6 Python applications to use Snowflake APIs (SQL, Python)

Client Manager Data Engineering

NielsenIQ

m 04/2017 - 10/2020

Bentonville, AR

Led team of 4 in scaling data warehousing and BI platforms for Walmart and Sam's Club

- Owned product management lifecycle through discovery, creating wire frames, data visualization mockups, user acceptance testing (UAT), client demos, and SQL deep
- Built POS and syndicated Panel data models, schemas, and ETL as a backbone to analytic products (Snowflake, SQL Server, Azure, Python, VisualCron)
- Enriched Nielsen Insight Studio to serve data analytics for 100's of merchants and analysts (MicroStrategy, SQL Server)
- Launched email based scorecards targeting senior merchants and Regional VP's (Python, HTML/CSS, VisualCron)
- Automated category reviews, saving 1400+ hours annually (Python, SQL, ReactJS, NodeJS, VisualCron)

Project Manager

Walmart

= 06/2016 - 04/2017

Bentonville, AR

Identified cost savings for Produce Global Logistics in TL + LTL performance

· Optimized data analysis by 60% (Python, SQL, Tableau, Alteryx)

Supply Chain Manager

Walmart

= 01/2015 - 06/2016

Bentonville, AR

Surfaced supply chain opportunities to Apparel merchandising leadership

· Increasing data visibility raised MABD compliance 9% (VBA, SQL, Tableau, Alteryx)

Data Analyst

Launch Marketing

Managed Retail Link extracts and reporting for 15 Walmart CPGs (VBA, Tableau)

CERTIFICATION

Building Resilient Streaming Analytics Systems on Google Cloud - June 2024

Modernizing Data Lakes and Data Warehouses with Google Cloud - May 2024

Google Cloud Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals - May 2024